A battle fought in the stars...now comes to Earth.
Masters of the Universe is a action, fantasy, science
fiction film directed by Gary Goddard.
When the evil Skeletor finds a mysterious power called the Cosmic Key, he becomes
nearly invincible, seizing Castle Grayskull and the surrounding city.
The Sorceress is now Skeletor's prisoner and he begins to drain her life-force as he waits for the moon of
Eternia to align with the Great Eye of the Universe which will bestow god-like power upon him.
However, courageous warrior He-Man locates the locksmith inventor
Gwildor, who created the Key and has another version of it.
During a battle, one of the Keys is transported to Earth,
where it is found by teenagers Julie and Kevin.
Now, both He-Man and Skeletor's forces arrive on
Earth searching for the potent weapon.
He-Man, played by Dolph Lundgren.
Skeletor, played by Frank Langella.
Evil-Lyn, played by Meg Foster.
Gwildor, played by Billy Barty.
Man At Arms, played by Jon Cypher.
Teela, played by Chelsea Field.
Masters of the Universe (stylized as Masters of the Universe: The Motion Picture) is a 1987
American superhero film based on the Masters of the Universe franchise by Mattel.
The film was directed by Gary Goddard, produced by Yoram Globus
and Menahem Golan, and written by David Odell.
It stars Dolph Lundgren, Frank Langella, Jon Cypher, Chelsea Field, Billy
Barty, Courteney Cox, Robert Duncan McNeill and Meg Foster.
The film follows Julie Winston and Kevin Corrigan, two teenagers who meet He-Man, the most powerful man in the universe, who travels to Earth with his friends, Man-At-Arms and
Teela, to stop their archenemy, the evil Skeletor from obtaining a cosmic key that will enable him to take over their home planet, Eternia, and the entire universe.
While it is the first live action movie in the franchise, the very first He-Man/Masters of The Universe movie was the
animated He-Man and She-Ra: The Secret of the Sword, released in theaters nationwide two years earlier in 1985.
Masters of the Universe was released theatrically in
the United States on August 7, 1987.
It was a critical and commercial failure, grossing $17
million worldwide against a budget of $22 million.
At the time of release, it was met with negative reviews from
film critics, but is now regarded as a cult film.
Another film adaptation which is set to release in 2026.
The film explores themes of skeleton, hero, saving the world, key, wretch.
The tone is thought_provoking and intense.